http://www.spiceroads.com/privacy

Destinations
Southeast AsiaEast AsiaSouth AsiaCentral AsiaEuropeAfricaMulti CountryMiddle East
Search
Southeast AsiaBurmaCambodiaIndonesiaLaosMalaysiaPhilippinesThailandVietnamEast AsiaChinaJapanSouth KoreaTaiwanSouth AsiaBhutanIndiaNepalSri LankaCentral AsiaKazakhstanMongoliaEuropeAlbaniaBosnia & HerzegovinaBulgariaCroatiaGeorgiaMacedoniaMontenegroTurkeyAfricaMadagascarMoroccoTanzaniaUgandaMulti CountryMiddle EastIsraelJordan
Day Tours
See a whole newside of a city
Touring
Classic touring inmindblowing places
Road
Push your body,feast your senses
Trails
Jungles, rivers,mountains and more
About SpiceRoads
Why SpiceRoads?
Staff
Careers
Media
Newsletter
Privacy Policy
Contact Us
About Our Tours
Travel Advice
At SpiceRoads, we’re committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This policy explains when and why we collect personal information about people who visit this website, www.spiceroads.com, how we use it, and how we keep it secure.
What type of information is collected and how is it used?
SpiceRoads might collect personal information from visitors and customers under the following circumstances:
Sending a Tour Enquiry
If you contact SpiceRoads with questions about our tours or other services, we will collect your name, email address, and your message in order to respond to your request.
Downloading a Tour Factsheet
If you download a tour Factsheet or send a tour enquiry, we will use email to communicate with you with the address you provide. Your email address may be stored in our system so we can follow up on your enquiries.
Subscribing to our Mailing List
If you subscribe to the SpiceRoads newsletter, we will send you information about SpiceRoads tours and products, company news and events, and special offers about twice per month, though occasionally it may be more than that. If you have been on a SpiceRoads tour and have not subscribed to our newsletter, we might contact you if we have an upcoming tour or departure that we think might interest you.
If you don’t want to receive newsletters, you can click on the link labelled “Unsubscribe” at the bottom of any email newsletter you receive from us.
Booking a Tour
If you book a SpiceRoads tour, we use forms to collect contact data you provide so that we can arrange your cycle tour and provide support. We will only use this information when it’s important to contact you as we prepare for your tour departure. This information is stored in our database and can be accessed by SpiceRoads office staff in order to assist you with booking or payment if necessary.
To book a tour, you will need to create a SpiceRoads account. This requires your name and email address. This account will also be used to update a booking or pay for a tour.
When booking a tour, SpiceRoads will collect your contact information including, your name, email address, and date of birth. Additionally, you may provide us with your mailing address, telephone number, and fax number. Because a cycling tour is an adventure experience service, we will also need to collect a name and number for an emergency contact individual to contact in the event of an emergency while on tour.
As a licensed tour operator, SpiceRoads is required to have your passport number and expiration date in many of the countries in which we operate. This information is also required in order to book and provide international travel services that are a part of your tour, such as accommodation and transportation, or to assist with visa and air ticket bookings.
Closer to your departure time, we will also collect information essential to providing our tour services to you, such as any medical conditions you might have that our tour leaders need to be aware of, any dietary requirements that might need special attention, your travel insurance provider and policy number, and your arrival and departing flight numbers and times. Most importantly, we will collect your height details in order to provide you with the correct size bike, should you choose to hire one of ours.
Receiving Post-Tour Surveys
After each tour we will send you a feedback survey to complete. These surveys are used as a way to monitor and improve our services. We value all or any feedback you are happy to provide. Participation in these surveys is completely optional and you have the choice whether or not to disclose this information.
Cookies
Our site uses cookies to for the following purposes:
to personalize your website experience by remembering user interface choices such as currency preference
to personalize your website experience by suggesting different tours and products to you, based on which tour pages you have already viewed
to track your visit on our website in order to launch a Live Chat feature, should you wish to contact us immediately via this function
to track which web pages you visit and how long you spend on them so that we can analyze website traffic and continue to improve our website for visitors
and to remember your visit to our website to distribute online advertisements
IP Addresses
When you visit our website we record the IP address of the device you are using to access the website in our web server log files, along with details of all requests for pages your browser sends to the server and errors that occur in processing those requests. These records are used as part of our efforts to maintain system security - they allow us to recognize and investigate suspicious access patterns and also debug issues with our applications. When you make a booking we store your IP address on the booking record in our database record and geo-locate it to provide data on where, geographically, our bookings coming from. Web server log files are retained for 100 days before being permanently deleted.
Google Analytics
SpiceRoads uses Google Analytics to measure how visitors interact with www.spiceroads.com, to analyze our website performance and make website changes and improvements based on those data. The information collected by Google Analytics does not reveal your identity or include personally identifying information. The information collected does include the content visitors view view, the date and amount of time viewing this content, whether an enquiry or booking was made, location information associated with visitors' IP address, and from which sources visitors accessed our website.
Online Advertising
Information about website traffic might be used with Google Adwords remarketing services and Facebook Advertising services to display SpiceRoads product advertisements on other websites and on Facebook, respectively. This could mean that if you search on our site, make an enquiry or download a factsheet, you might see our advertisement on the Google search results page, on a site within the Google Display Network, in your Facebook Newsfeed, or the right-side column of your Facebook Newsfeed.
Any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy and Google’s and Facebook’s own privacy policies. You can set preferences for how these services advertise to you using the Google Ad Preferences and Facebook Advertising Preferences pages, and if you do not wish to receive this type of advertising from us in the future you can opt out of interest-based advertising entirely within those settings.
Is your information shared with third parties?
SpiceRoads will never sell or share your information with third parties.
We may pass your information to a third party service provider in order to provide services to you on our behalf. After completion of a tour, we will send a feedback survey through Survey Gizmo to the email address you have provided to us in order to learn more about your experience with SpiceRoads and improve our services. View SurveyGizmo’s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy.
If you are subscribed to our newsletter, we will provide MailChimp, our email marketing service provider, with your email address in order to send you and other subscribers our email newsletters and any other important email notices. Read MailChimp’s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy.
Your information is never used for the third party’s marketing purposes, and is protected by that third party’s own privacy policy and practices.
Please note that payment information used in paying a tour deposit or tour cost is collected by third party payment processors who specialize in secure online capture and processing of payment transactions.
How can you access and update your information and preferences?
If the information we hold about you, such as your email address, is inaccurate or out of date, please email us at
to correct or update it.
If you wish to have a copy of the information SpiceRoads holds about you, we are able to provide you with details of the information. Please email your request to us at .
How is your information protected?
SpiceRoads follows what we consider to be appropriate data protection practices in the context of the personal data we store and process. On the technical side, all access to computer systems by system administrators is done over secure connections. Internally our application servers and database servers all communicate over encrypted channels. And access to our website is only available over TLS. Thus data in transit is always encrypted and protected from snooping.
Operationally, SpiceRoads staff must be authenticated and have specific roles assigned before they can access customer data held by our systems.
When making a booking, you will be asked to provide personal data which SpiceRoads considers strictly necessary in order to effectively process your booking and provide service to you. As your departure approaches, we’ll request more information from you which is required in order to operate the tour. Customer data is stored indefinitely.
In the event of a data breach, we'll contact the Supervisory Authority in the countries of those potentially affected by the breach as and where appropriate. We'll also contact the individuals potentially affected to let them know what has happened and what steps we are taking to rectify the situation in the event that it poses any risk to their rights or security.
Links to other websites
The SpiceRoads website may contain links to other websites run by other organisations, and may be linked to from other third party sites. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners and operators of other third party sites linked to or from our own.
Your Rights to Your Information
You have the right to request access to your information for the purpose of correcting your information, changing how your information is used, or erasing your information at any time. Please be aware that certain personal information is required in order to book, purchase, and participate on a SpiceRoads tour. For more details, please read “Booking a Tour.”
To request access to your information, please email , with “Privacy Enquiry - Information Request” in the subject line.
Changes to our Privacy Policy and Practices
We keep this policy under regular review. If we change our information handling practices or other privacy aspects, we will post those changes on this privacy statement.
This policy was last updated in May 2018.
Contact us
If you have any questions about our privacy policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with our website, you can contact us for further information by sending an email to .
You can also contact us by phone at +66 2 026 3295, or by post:
T.T.T. Tour Operator No. 14/02179 ATTA: 02354 Privacy Policy
